Based on the true case files of the Warrens.
The Conjuring is a horror, thriller film directed by James Wan.
Paranormal investigators Ed and Lorraine Warren work to help a
family terrorized by a dark presence in their farmhouse.
Forced to confront a powerful entity, the Warrens find themselves
caught in the most terrifying case of their lives.
Lorraine Warren, played by Vera Farmiga.
Ed Warren, played by Patrick Wilson.
Carolyn Perron, played by Lili Taylor.
Roger Perron, played by Ron Livingston.
Nancy, played by Hayley McFarland.
Judy Warren, played by Sterling Jerins.
The Conjuring is a 2013 American supernatural horror film directed
by James Wan and written by Chad Hayes and Carey W.
It is the inaugural film in The Conjuring Universe franchise.
Patrick Wilson and Vera Farmiga star as Ed and Lorraine Warren, paranormal
investigators and authors associated with prominent cases of haunting.
Their purportedly real-life reports inspired The Amityville
Horror story and the associated film franchise.
The Warrens come to the assistance of the Perron family, who experienced increasingly
disturbing events in their newly occupied farmhouse in Rhode Island in 1971.
Development of the film began in January 2012 and reports confirmed Wan as the
director of a film entitled The Warren Files, later retitled The Conjuring.
Production began in Wilmington, North Carolina, in February
2012 and scenes were shot in chronological order.
The Conjuring was released in the United States and
Canada on July 19, 2013, by Warner Bros.
It received positive reviews from critics and grossed over $319
million worldwide against its $20 million budget.
A sequel, The Conjuring 2, was released in 2016.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship,
1970s, cellar, exorcism, haunted house.
The tone is dark and intense.